stats.com 2019-04-22

# Copyright | STATS

STATS LLC is committed to protecting your personal information and respecting your privacy in accordance with applicable laws.

This Privacy Policy tells you about how and why we collect and use the personal data which you provide to us or which we collect about you when you interact with us, for example, when you use our website or we meet you at tradeshows or other events.

We want you to be fully informed about how we use your data, how we keep it secure and your rights  
We trust this Privacy Policy will answer any questions you have, but if not, please get in touch with us using the contact details provided at the end of this Privacy Policy.

We may need to update this Privacy Policy from time to time by updating this page. We will notify you of any significant changes, but would encourage you to come back and review it from time to time.

**ABOUT US – WHO IS THE STATS GROUP?**

This Privacy Policy is provided by STATS LLC and our STATS’ group companies (referred to as “we”, “us” or “our” in this Privacy Policy). We are the data controller of any personal data we collect about you and we are responsible for the STATS website at (www.stats.com).

STATS is a global company with offices and operations located around the world. This includes offices in France, Spain, the Netherlands, UK, Germany, Denmark, Ireland, Australia, New Zealand, China, and India. For further details, please contact us using the details provided at the end of this Privacy Policy. When we refer to the ‘STATS group’ we are referring to the wider global group of STATS companies.

**ENSURING THE LAWFUL USE OF YOUR DATA**

We will only use your personal data where we have a lawful basis to use it. We will usually only use your data where it is necessary for us to perform under a contract with you (for example, to provide you with the services you have requested), or in a way which might reasonably be expected as part of running our business and which does not materially impact your interests, rights or freedoms. Please contact us using the details below if you would like further information about this.

We may sometimes need to use data to comply with our legal obligations (for example to pass on details of people who are involved in fraud). In some cases we will ask for your consent to use your data, for example, where you sign-up to receive our email newsletters or access to our blogs.

Further details of how we will use your personal information are provided below.

**WHAT INFORMATION WE COLLECT FROM YOU AND HOW WE USE IT**

The information we collect about you and how we will use it, depends on how you interact with us, for example, if you request services from us or contact us with a query by email or phone. The table below provides some examples of the information we collect about you and how we will use it.

**The personal data we collect from you** | **How we use it** | **Lawful Basis**  
---|---|---  
We will collect the personal data needed to identify you such as your name, username and password. We will also collect your contact details, such as your email address, telephone number, job title, mailing address/place of work. | To enter into a business relationship with you: to provide our services and to contact you about them where necessary. We use Marketo to collect contact information and Salesforce to collect opportunity information | Legitimate business purpose and to fulfil our contract with you.  
To allow you to create an account with us. | Legitimate business purposes.  
To send you email newsletters, interesting blogs, forum updates, news webinars and articles relating to sports and to keep you up-to-date about our products and services which we think will interest you. | Where you consent.  
To allow you to attend an event. | Legitimate business purposes  
So that you can enter competitions, or events run by us. | Legitimate business purposes  
If you raise an enquiry or complaint with us. | Legitimate business purposes  
To allow you to complete any surveys we send you (if you wish to) or to comment on or review our products or services, to help us to improve them. | Legitimate business purposes  
Fraud prevention and detection | Legal obligation/legitimate business purposes  
Payment details and details of your transactions. | To take payment for our products and services. This payment information is processed by STATS’ third party service provider, BluePay. STATS will share this data with credit card companies and other payment providers. | To fulfil our contract with you.  
Fraud prevention and detection | Legal obligation/legitimate business purposes  
Information you provide to us when you contact us by telephone, by email. | Provide you with the support and customer service you have requested. | Legitimate business purposes  
To train our employees. | Legitimate business purposes  
Technical information about your browsing actions and patterns. We collect this personal data by using cookies and other similar technologies and full details as to how we process and use cookies can be found on our [Cookies Policy](https://www.stats.com/cookie-policy/) | To administer and to improve our Website, to ensure it is presented in the most effective manner for you and to give you the best Website experience and to allow you to participate in interactive features of our Website if you choose to do so. | Legitimate business purposes  
For data analysis, testing, research to help us to improve our products and services. | Legitimate business purposes  
To keep our Website safe and secure. | Legitimate business purposes  
To make suggestions and recommendations to you and other users of our Website about products or services that may interest you or them. | Legitimate business purposes  
To measure or understand the effectiveness of advertising we serve to you and others, and to deliver relevant advertising to you. | Legitimate business purposes  
  
You do not have to give us any of the personal data set out above but, if you do not provide us with certain information, we may not be able to provide you with the products and services you have requested from us. The forms you fill in on our Website will make it clear what information we need in order to provide the product or service you are requesting and what information you can choose to provide if you wish.

**AUTOMATED DECISION MAKING** ** **

We do not currently carry out any solely automated decision-making using information we hold about you.

**SHARING YOUR DATA**

**SHARING YOUR DATA WITHIN THE STATS GROUP**

STATS may share your personal data with other companies within the STATS Group to enable us to develop new products, run data analysis, and for other business development purposes and/or to allow them to perform services e.g. such as the processing of match-related event data, and the creation of reports, on our behalf pursuant to a customer contract. Where we do this, we have written contracts in place between the companies within the STATS group to ensure your privacy is secure and respected.

**SHARING YOUR DATA WITH TRUSTED THIRD PARTIES**

We share your personal data with trusted third parties to allow us to provide our services to you. When we do share your data with these third parties, STATS will enter into written contracts with them, which require them to only use your data for the purpose we specify to them and that your privacy is secure and respected.

These trusted third parties include the following:

  * Professional service providers such as website hosting providers, credit card payment processor (i.e. BluePay) system providers, website analytics providers, companies who help us manage contact information from prospective customers (e.g. Marketo and Cloudingo) and to process opportunities with actual customers, e.g. Salesforce, all to help us run our business;
  * Credit reference agencies, law enforcement and fraud prevention agencies, so we can help tackle fraud.

We may also share your personal data:

  * in connection with a business transition (such as a merger, acquisition by another company, or a sale of all of or portion of our assets). In these circumstances, we may need to share your personal data with a prospective buyer and external professional advisors such as accountants, insurers, lawyers or financial institutions.
  * Where we have a duty or a legal obligation to do so, such as with the police, administrative authorities, other enforcement, regulatory or Government bodies, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements, or in order to enforce or apply our Terms and Conditions.

**INFORMATION WE RECEIVE FROM THIRD PARTIES**

We may receive information about you from publicly available sources, such as LinkedIn or information which is published in the media.

We may combine the information you have given us, with information obtained from other sources, but we will only do this when we have a lawful basis to do so.

**INTERNATIONAL TRANSFER OF YOUR PERSONAL DATA** ** **

We are a global business head-quartered in the US. This means that your personal data may be transferred to or accessed from outside the EU/EEA in a jurisdiction that is not governed by EU data protection laws. However, safeguards are in place to protect personal data, as set out below.

STATS LLC will process personal data in the US for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy. Any transfers of personal data from STATS group entities in the EU to STATS LLC in the US will be protected by the EU-U.S Privacy Shield Frameworks (“Privacy Shield”) administered by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding STATS’ collection and use of personal data from the European Union member countries. STATS adheres to the following privacy policy in connection with its receipt and processing of personal data from the European Union (EU) for use in the context of the relationship (as identified above) under the Privacy Shield. STATS agrees to cooperate with the EU data protection authorities and comply with the advice given by such authorities with respect to this personal data. STATS has certified that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles of notice, choice, accountability for onward transfer, security, data integrity, and purpose limitation, access, recourse, enforcement and liability. STATS is subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the Federal Trade Commission. To learn more about the Privacy Shield Principles, and to view STATS’ certification, please visit www.privacyshield.gov. STATS is registered with International Centre for Dispute Resolution/American Arbitration Association (ICDR/AAA) who will act as STATS’ alternative dispute resolution provider in the event that any privacy concerns are not resolved by STATS. You may contact ICDR/AAA at <http://go.adr.org/privacyshield.html>. Alternative dispute resolution will be at STATS’ expense. Under certain conditions, you may invoke binding arbitration. Please access the above links for further information or contact us using the details provided at the end of this Privacy Policy.

Personal data may be processed by other STATS entities (other than STATS LLC in the US) located outside the EU/EEA from time to time, e.g. STATS Systems India Private Limited and STATS Analytics Australia Pty. Ltd in order to fulfill STATS’ contract obligations to provide services to a customer. When this occurs, the transfer is protected by Standard Contractual Clauses which have been entered into by the relevant STATS entities located outside the EU/EEA.

A number of our service providers are also located (or will access your personal data from) outside the EU/EEA, e.g. Salesforce, Marketo, and BluePay. In all such cases, we will enter into Standard Contractual Clauses to safeguard the data. In certain circumstances, STATS may be liable under the Privacy Shield if these service providers who perform services on our behalf, process such personal data in a manner inconsistent with the Privacy Shield. For more information about Standard Contractual Clauses, see <https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/data-transfers-outside-eu/model-contracts-transfer-personal-data-third-countries>.

**HOW LONG WILL WE KEEP YOUR PERSONAL DATA?** ** **

We will only keep your personal data for as long as we need to for the reason we collected it, as set out in this Privacy Policy. For example, for as long as needed to allow us to provide our services or to provide any support you have requested.

We may also keep hold of some of your personal data if we are required to do so for legal purposes, for example, to meet our legal or regulatory requirements or to prevent fraud and abuse.

** ** **SECURITY** ** **

We are committed to ensuring that your personal data is secure and we have put in place suitable administrative, technical, physical, contractual and managerial measures, including our information security management system, to protect your personal data from loss, theft, unauthorised use, disclosure or modification, including encryption, where appropriate. Our employees who have access to and process your personal data are obliged to respect the confidentiality and security of your personal data. In addition, we have appropriate measures in place to make sure that the personal data it retains is accurate and up-to-date.

**HOW CAN I UNSUBSCRIBE FROM MARKETING COMMUNICATIONS?**

You can unsubscribe from our marketing communications by visiting our preference centre at <http://go.stats.com/SubscriptionCenter.html> or by contacting us at any time using the details provided at the end of this Privacy Policy.

**YOUR RIGHTS**

You have the following rights in relation to the personal information we hold about you, to request:

  * access to the personal data we hold about you (commonly known as a “data subject access request”) including a copy of it;
  * the correction of the personal information that we hold about you if it is incomplete or inaccurate;
  * the deletion or removal of personal data we hold about you where there is no good reason for us continuing to process it or where you have exercised your right to object to processing (see below);
  * for our processing of your personal information to be restricted in certain circumstances, for example if you want to establish its accuracy or the reason for processing it; and
  * to obtain a copy of the personal information you’ve provided us with and to reuse it elsewhere or to ask us to transfer it to a third party of your choice.
  * To withdraw any consent you have provided to our use of your personal data. Where you withdraw consent we will stop using your data for the specific purpose, unless we have an alternative legal basis to use it.

We may ask you for proof of your identity before dealing with your request, as a security measure to protect your data.

**Right to Object**

Where we are processing your personal data on the basis of our legitimate interests, you can ask us to stop processing it and we must do so unless we believe we have an overriding legitimate reason to continue processing your personal data.

If you are dissatisfied with how we have handled your personal data, you have the right to make a complaint to your data protection regulator and we will work with them to resolve it. We would, however, appreciate the chance to deal with your concerns before you approach the regulator, so please do contact us in the first instance.

**CHILDREN** ** **

Customers need to be over 16 to create an account with us or to sign up for our newsletter. We will not knowingly collect data about under 16 and if you are under 16, please do not provide us with your personal information. We would ask parents to please ensure that their children that are under 16 do not provide us with any personal information without their permission. If you believe that a child who is under 16 has provided personal data to us, please contact us, using the details below and we will seek to delete that data from our systems.

**CONTACTING US**

If you have any queries, comments or requests regarding this Privacy Policy, you have a complaint or you would like to exercise any of your rights set out above, you can contact us in the following ways:

**by email**  
to STATS’ Data Protection Officer, Lillian Pang, Taceo Limited, Tel: +44 7474 293 610

**by post**  
STATS LLC (Privacy)  
Attention: Legal Department/Data Protection Officer  
203 North LaSalle St. Suite 2200  
Chicago, IL 60601  
United States

**by phone**  
847-583-2100 (ask for the Legal Department)

_This Privacy Policy was last updated on 25 May 2018._
